A Guide to the Paul Ehrlich papers FA135
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Hedwig Ehrlich's correspondence, after Paul Ehrlich's death
  - Neisser, Max, 1916 January 30; 1 letter (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Neuman, Alfred, 1916 March 26 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    Typescript copy of this letter is in Reminiscence File Folder #7.
  - Sachs, Alice, 1933 May 5, 12 (2); 1 letter (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Schwerin, Hans, 1933 June 15; 1 letter (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Shiga, Kiyoshi Photograph of Shiga at age 79, letter; handwritten and typescript synopsis by Hedwig Ehrlich, 1940 (4) (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Unknown sender (1) not complete, 1915 September 7 (Box 51, Folder 22)
- Tapes of Testimonial Dinner, 1941 October (Box 52)
  2 tapes of speeches given at a dinner in honor for Hedwig Ehrlich, October 1941 at the Waldorf-Astoria Hotel. One tape contains a radio address and dinner speech by Hedwig Ehrlich. The other tape contains a speech written by Father Schwitala S.J. but because of his illness was read by Father Burger S.J. The applause in the radio address is dubbed in.
- Centennial Celebration, Frankfurt, 1954 March
  - 1 photo album presented to Stefanie Schwerin (Box 53)
  - 1 booklet with text and pictures describing the event (Box 53)
  - The British Medical Journal (Box 53)
    2 copies (both with articles referring to the celebration and individual articles by Dale, Browning and Marquardt).
    - 1954 March 20
    - 1954 March 27
  - 2 sheets by Hoechst announcing the celebration on one side and on the other side a print of a letter by Ehrlich to Hoechst, asking them to supply more diamidodioxyarsenobenzol (Box 53)
  - 3 copies of a typescript report on the celebration most likely by Stefanie Schwerin, 4 pages (Box 53)
  - 3 copies of a 2 page typescript report by Stefanie Schwerin, 2 pages (Box 53)
  - 1 copy each of a speech by Dr. R. Prigge, Director of the Paul Ehrlich Institute, typescript (Box 53)
    - "Begrüssungsansprache", March 14, 1954, opening speech, 1954 March 14; 1
    - "Ansprache bei der Kranzniederlegung", speech at the grave of Ehrlich, March 14, 1954, 1954 March 14; 2
    - "Ansprache zur Proklamation des Ehrlich-Behring Jahres", speech proclaiming 1954 the year of Ehrlich and Behring, 3
  - 1 letter by Dr. A. Stühmer to Stefanie Schwerin with 3 copies of an article about Ehrlich, all 3 inscribed, letter dated March 30, 1954, Freiburg, 1954 March 30 (Box 53)
  - 1 telegram to Stefanie Schwerin by Viebrock, Rector of the University of Frankfurt, commemorating the 50th anniversary of Ehrlich's Nobel Prize receipt, dated, 1958 November 28 (Box 53)
  - 1 letter by Günther Schwerin to the secretary of the Centennial celebration, requesting the invitation of Martha Marquardt, who had not been invited, dated, 1954 February 19 (Box 53)
  - 1 telegram in answer to this letter, 1954 February 28 (Box 53)
  - 1 letter of the secretary to Günther Schwerin, explaining why Miss Marquardt received her invitation only now, 1954 March 4 (Box 53)
  - 1 invitation to the celebration for Günther Schwerin (Box 53)
  - 1 handwritten note (G. Schwerin?) maybe a draft of a telegram (Box 53)
- Books and Speeches (Box 53)
  - Satter, Heinrich, Paul Ehrlich, Begründer der Chemotherapie, March 1963 Vorträge (lectures) 2 copies each in German and English photocopies of newspaper, with English text 100 year celebration at the New York Academy of Medicine, 1963 March
  - 2 copies of program, 1 copy of lectures given on that occasion Book entitled: Hessen, Kultur und Wirtschaft
- Movie material: Dr. Ehrlich's Magic Bullet
  - 2 typewritten dialogue transcripts (Package 6)
  - 56 photographs, 1 with inscription to Hedwig Ehrlich by E.G. Robinson and 1 by Ruth Gordon, many duplicates (Package 6)
  - 17 paper clippings, mostly reviews of the movie, many duplicates (Package 6)
  - 3 typewritten letters to Hedwig Ehrlich by E.G. Robinson, 2 in English, 1 in German (Package 6)
  - 1 telegram to H. Ehrlich from E.G. Robinson (Package 6)
  - Nobel Diploma in case. Honorary doctorate diploma, University of Breslau, in case (Package 7)
- Hedwig Ehrlich: Recipes, American diaries and memorabilia
  - 5 folders of handwritten recipes (Package 8)
  - 2 black notebooks with recipes (Package 8)
  - 1 handwritten cookbook (Package 8)
  - 2 black leather etuis (Package 8)
  - 1 wicker basket with a few dried flowers (originally contained engagement correspondence) (Package 8)
  - 2 address books (America years) (Package 8)
  - 1 desk check book Dec. 11, 1947-Dec. 8, 1948 (Hedwig Ehrlich's death), then her estate Dec. '48 to Jan. '52, 1947 December 11-1948 December 8 (Package 8)
  - 2 expenditure account books, 1933-1948 (Package 8)
  - 1 box with sweater clips (Package 8)
  - 1 leather box empty (Package 8)
  - 1 etui (leather) with Hedwig Ehrlich calling cards (Package 8)
  - 8 small diaries, 1942-1949 (Package 8)
- Hedwig Ehrlich: Records of testimonial dinner speeches and Stefanie Schwerin: Album and wreath band
  - Records of speeches honoring Hedwig Ehrlich in 1941 at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel (Package 9)
  - Album of pictures and poems made by Hans Schwerin in honor of Stefanie Schwerin's 80th birthday (Package 9)
  - Trauerschleife: silk band with golden fringes which was attached to the wreath, given by the President of West Germany at the occasion of Stefanie Schwerin's funeral in 1961 (Package 9)
- Embroidered etui made from birch bark containing 2 handkerchiefs and embroidered purses
  - 1 lace handkerchief with label in Auguste Pinkus, nee Fränker's handwriting: Mein Brauttaschentuch 16 Juli 1856, 1856 July 16 (Package 10)
  - 1 embroidered handkerchief with label in Auguste's hand: Geschenk meines Bräutigams Josef Pinkus. 3 gestickte Taschentücher 1 embroidered purse with ribbon. Label in Hedwig Ehrlich's hand: Paul Ehrlich's Tascheam 1sten Geburtstage (Package 10)
  - 1 blue velvet purse; "Paul" embroidered in gold, with gold string, labeled in H. Ehrlich's handwriting: Paul Ehrlich's Jahrestasche (Package 10)
- Books
  - Bulloch, William. The History of Bacteriology, Oxford University Press, London 1938
  - Flechtner, Hans-Joachim. Gesundheit durch Krankheit, Econ Verlag, Düsseldorf, 1954
  - Galdston, Iago. Behind the Sulfa Drugs, D. Appleton-Century, New York, London, 1943
  - Gerhardt, Oswald. Mikroben im Weltgeschehen, Paul List Verlag, Munchen, 1954 (2 copies)
  - Herter, Christian. Imagination and Idealism in the Medical Sciences, address given on September 23, 1909. By Herter at the opening of the medical school at Columbia University. This book was sent to Hedwig with an inscription by some member of the Herter family in October 1941
  - de Kruif, Paul. Microbe Hunters, Pocket Books, Inc. New York 1926 (2 copies. The second copy is called: Dr. Ehrlich's
  - de Kruif, Paul. Magic Bullet and the Discovery of 11 Other Microbe Hunters
  - Lazarus, Adolf. Paul Ehrlich - Meister der Heilkunde, Rikola Verlag, 1922, 5 copies, 1 is corrector's copy
  - Loewe, Hans. Paul Ehrlich, Schöpfer der Chemotherapie, Wissenschaftliche Verlagsgesellschaft, Stuttgart, 1950 (2 copies)
  - Marquardt, Martha. Paul Ehrlich - Als Mensch und Arbeiter, Deutsche Verlags Anstalt, Stuttgart, 1924 (8 copies, with dedications to Hedwig Ehrlich, Hans and Stefanie Schwerin)
  - Marquardt, Martha. Paul Ehrlich, William Heineman Books, London, 1949 in English, with a dedication to Stefanie Schwerin
  - Neisser, Albert. Paul Ehrlich, Springer Verlag, Berlin, 1951 in German Obituary in book form, unknown editor, obviously part of another book, pp. 558-578
  - Satter, Heinrich. Paul Ehrlich, Begründer der Chemotherapie, Verlag und Graphische Betriebe, Oldenbourg 1962, 3 copies
  - Schülein, Julius. Die Bierhefe als Heil-Nahr-und Futtermittel Steinkopff Verlag, Dresden and Leipzig, 1932
  - Shiga, Kiyoshi. Paul Ehrlich biography in Japanese, with inscription to Hedwig Ehrlich, chapters are marked In English
  - Steuerwald, Willy. Friedliche Eroberer, Paul Ehrlich, Grieshab and
  - Venzmer, Gerhard. Säuberlich, Stuttgart - Tübingen, 1948 Eine Sterbende Krankheit - vom Aufstieg und Niedergang der Syphilis, Montana Verlag, Leipzig, 1929 (2 copies, 1 with a dedication to Hedwig Ehrlich) Paul Ehrlich - Leben und Wirken, Mundug Verlag Stuttgart, 1948 (7 copies, 2 copies have signatures of participants of the Centennial Celebration in 1954. One copy is in Spanish)
  - Venzmer. Annual Reports of the Paul Ehrlich Institute, 1924 1950 1951 1952
    Includes: Dr. Owsei Tmkin, Dr. Saul Jarcho, and Dr. David Shakow.
  - Venzmer. Annual Report of the Behringwerk, 1954
- Bronze plaque featuring Paul Ehrlich in profile 11x16. "Zum 14. März 1904, Die Schule und Mitarbeiter"
- Etching of Paul Ehrlich en face, framed (Unverstählt, I Druck); 14.5 × 19.5
- Newly Collected Paul Ehrlich Material Deposited by Gunther K. Schwerin
  - Copies of Paul Ehrlich's letters to Franz Sachs 1898-1911 (176). Originals are at the Leo Baeck Institute in New York, 176 letters (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Copies of Paul Ehrlich's letters to Kitasato 1898-1912 (18). Originals at the Kitasato Institute in Japan (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Copies of Paul Ehrlich related material sent by Dr. Toju Hata in 1982, 12 letters (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Article about Joseph Pinkus (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Material regarding the Paul Ehrlich Prize in 1980 and 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Material regarding the Paul Ehrlich exhibit in Frankfurt in 1981 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Article about the Paul Ehrlich Institute in 1899 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Copy of a speech by Dr. Hans Harken at the dedication of the Paul Ehrlich wing in the Weizmann Institute, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Documents found during research by B.I. Hirsch after the material had been sorted and listed (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - 3 letters by Paul Ehrlich, typescripts (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - (1) second half of letter to E. Von Leyden, no date, no sig, undated
    - (1) letter to Werner & Winter with sig, 1904
    - (1) letter to Zimmer & Co., no sig, 1904
  - Tracing of a small hand with poem, 1885 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Request for an autograph from Paul Ehrlich by Homer Norris, 1909 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Article entitled "Darwin, der Forscher" with red pen marks which could be Paul Ehrlich's (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Photograph of Hedwig Pinkus and Paul Ehrlich, circa 1883. This picture was given to Gunther Schwerin by Bernhard Witkop Pamphlet "Steglitzer Heimat", Nr. 1, June 1, 1965 containing an article about the Steglitz Institute (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Article by Bernhard Witkop, entitled: Paul Ehrlich: His Ideas and His Legacy, presented at the Nobel Symposium 52, held in Sweden August 1981 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Article by James G. Hirsch and Beate I. Hirsch, entitled: Paul Ehrlich and the Discovery of the Eosinophil, Grune and Stratton, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Speech given by Dr. George Cross, from The Rockefeller University, on March 14, 1984, when he received the Paul Ehrlich- Ludwig Darmstadter Prize in Frankfurt, 1984 March 14 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Speech by Dr. Bernhard Witkop on March 14, 1984, at the grave of Paul Ehrlich in Frankfurt, 1984 March 14 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Necrology of Paul Ehrlich by Carl Ludwig Schleich, 1915 (Box 54, Folder 15)
- Translation of Paul Ehrlich Material by James G. Hirsch and Beate I. Hirsch
  - Hirsch translation of "Copir Buch II". Original book is in Box No. 4. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of November 11, 1898-February 21, 1899, 1898 November 11-1899 February 21 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Hirsch translation of "Copir Buch III". Original copy book is in Box No. 5. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of February 21, 1899-July 31, 1899, 1899 February 21-July 31 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Hirsch translation of "Copir Buch IV". Original copy book is in Box No. 6. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of August 1, 1899-March 1, 1900, 1899 August 1-1900 March 1 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Hirsch translation of "Zettel Buch I". Original copy book is in Box No. 7. It contains copies of laboratory instructions written by Paul Ehrlich to his co-workers at the Institute and covers the period of February 1, 1900-December 26, 1900, 1900 February 1-December 26 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Hirsch translation of "Zettel Buch II". Original copy book is in Box No. 8. It contains copies of laboratory instructions written by Paul Ehrlich to his co-workers at the Institute and covers the period of December 25, 1900-September 21, 1901, 1900 December 25-1901 September 21 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Hirsch translation of "Zettel Buch III". Original copy book is in Box No. 9. It contains copies of laboratory instructions written by Paul Ehrlich to his co-workers at the Institute and covers the period of January 22, 1902-December 2, 1902, 1902 January 22-December 2 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Hirsch translation continues with Paul Ehrlich correspondence (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich IX". Original copy book is in Box No. 21. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of September 25, 1902-December 23, 1902, 1902 September 25-December 23 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich X". Original copy book is in Box No. 22. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of December 23, 1902-March 19, 1903, 1902 December 23-1903 March 19 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich XI". Original copy book is in Box No. 23. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of March 19, 1903-July 17, 1903, 1903 March 19-July 17 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich XIII". Original copy book is in Box No. 23. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of December 21, 1903-June 13, 1904, 1903 December 21-1904 June 13 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich XV". Original copy book is in Box No. 23. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of October 25, 1904-February 2, 1905, 1904 October 25-1905 February 2 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich XVI". Original copy book is in Box No. 23. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of February 6, 1905-April 22, 1905, 1905 February 6-April 22 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich XVII". Original copy book is in Box No. 24. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of April 20, 1905-August 4, 1905, 1905 April 20-August 4 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich XVIII". Original copy book is in Box No. 24. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of August 4, 1904-January 1, 1906, 1904 August 4-1906 January 1 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich XXII". Original copy book is in Box No. 24. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of May 5, 1907-November 1, 1907, 1907 May 5-November 1 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Hirsch translation of "Direktor Ehrlich XXIII". Original copy book is in Box No. 25. It contains copies of letters written by Paul Ehrlich and covers the period of November 1, 1907-April 9, 1908, 1907 November 1-1908 April 9 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Engagement letters written by Hedwig Pinkus to Paul Ehrlich, 1883 February 26-August 6 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    Typescript of original handwritten. The original letters are in Box No. 48.
  - Engagement letters written by Paul Ehrlich to Hedwig Pinkus, 1883 February 25-August 8 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    Typescript of original handwritten. The original letters are in Box No. 49.
  - Hirsch translation of engagement correspondence between Hedwig Pinkus and Paul Ehrlich, covering the period of February 26, 1883 August 8, 1883. Every letter has been translated, some were summarized, most translated literally, 1883 February 26-August 8 (Box 57, Folder 5)
- Other material added to the Collection
  This material was in an envelope sent by Dr. Herman Pinkus to Dr. Hans Aron, Chicago in December 1954.
  - 36 original letters, typed, with Paul Ehrlich signature, addressed to Dr. Heinrich Loeb in Mannheim, 1910 April 9-1915 April 1 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - 1 letter with Martha Marquardt signature (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - 2 telegrams from P.E. to Dr. Loeb (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - 1 letter from Loeb to P.E., 1910 November 10 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Typewritten list of names, presumably of those physicians who received 606 to treat patients, 1910-1918 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    Approx. 20 pieces of printed material related to the availability and administration of Salvarsan and Neosalvarsan, dating from 1910-1918.
  - Photocopies of the material in Folder 6 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Material from Herbert C. Friedmann, University of Chicago. Correspondence between H.C. Friedmann and Herman Pinkus regarding the Paul Ehrlich exhibit in Chicago in 1954. Original letter by Albert Neisser, as well as printed information on the use of Salvarsan and Neosalvarsan (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Reprint of article by Joshua Lederberg "Ontogeny of the Clonal Selection Theory of Antibody Formation. Reflections on Darwin and Ehrlich", 1988 December (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Photocopy of handwritten Paul Ehrlich note: "Corpora non argunt nisi fixata", Frankfurt, 1911 April 22 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Folder from Deutsche Bank with material regarding a new DM 200 currency with Paul Ehrlich's picture on it (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Photocopies of the following letters: 5 handwritten letters by Paul Ehrlich to Dr. Klemperer (no specific date) (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Letter by Paul Ehrlich to Dr. Klemperer, 1910 April 16; typewritten (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - 1 handwritten letter by Emil v. Behring, 1902 February 9 (Box 57, Folder 12)
- Material added from the estate of Hans Schwerin
  - Original diploma, signed Kaiser Wilhelm II, conferring the title "Wirklicher Geheimrath" to Paul Ehrlich (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Photo of Sir Canon Doyle with handwritten letter to Paul Ehrlich (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Framed page of a Paul Ehrlich Copy Book, page #174 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Framed handwritten letter by Paul Ehrlich to Hedwig Ehrlich, date? (Box 57, Folder 12)
- Correspondence
  Contains restricted material.
  - Several glass vials containing 606 and Neosalversan in powder form, undated (Box 58)
    Labels are handwritten by Paul Ehrlich.
  - Notes on a biography of Paul Ehrlich, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Biographical account of Paul Ehrlich, Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1970 April (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Pelner, Louis, "Paul Ehrlich, M.D. (1854-1915) Great Theoretician and Benefactor of Mankind" in New York State Journal of Medicine, 1971 October 1 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - 3,000 Biographies of the World's Most Famous Men and Women, 1940 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Burger, Alfred, "Paul Ehrlich" in Chemical and Engineering News vol. 32, pp. 4172-4176, 1954 October 18 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Warburg, Otto Heinrich, "Sonderdruck aus Die Grossen Deutschen" [German biography in 4 volumes - Journal], undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - "Verzeichnis - der im Besitz van Hans-Wolfgang Schwerin befindlichen Werke von und über Paul Ehrlich" [An Index of all the works by and about Paul Ehrlich in the possession of Hans Wolfgang Schwerin], undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Chronology of Paul Ehrlich compiled by Professor H. Sachs, undated (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Family Tree starting with Paul Ehrlich and Hedwig Pinkus, undated (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence between Paul Ehrlich and Farbewerke vorm. Meister Lucius and Brüning, 1894 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Diphtheria antitoxin, 1894-1897 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Diphtheria Antitoxin, 1892-1906 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    Contains restricted material
  - Diphtheria Antitoxin, 1894-1913 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    Contains restricted materials
  - Diphtheria Antitoxin, 1894-1913 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Hedwig Ehrlich - letters to F. Althoff [photostatic copies], 1896-1908 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Letters to F. Althoff [photostatic copies], 1890-1908 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Hedwig and Paul Ehrlich - letters to F. Althoff, 1890-1908 [Synopsis and Transcriptions by G.K. Schwerin] (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Letters to F. Althoff-F. Althofff[photostatic copies], 1890-1908 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Ministry of Berlin and two publications with contributions by Paul Ehrlich, 1902-1906 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Letters by Ehrlich to Dr. Flexner and Dr. Meltzer, 1910 January-March (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Ministry of Berlin regarding Award of Royal Kronen Orden, 1899 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Ministry Berlin regarding personnel matters, 1896-1900 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Vier Briefe von Paul Ehrlich an verschiedene Empfänger, April-May 1900 [Four letters from Paul Ehrlich to different recipients], 1900 April-May (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - 24 Briefe von Paul Ehrlich an Prof Dr. Martin Freund, Frankfurt Am Main, vor, 1899-1913 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Sammlung Darmstaedter, Briefe von Paul Ehrlich an Darmstaedter und Andere [Letters from Paul Ehrlich to Darmstaedter and others], 1899-1914 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Sammlung Darmstaedter, Briefe von Paul Ehrlich an Darmstaedter und Andere, 1899-1914 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    [Including inventory list with brief description of contents].
  - Correspondence, 1917 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    Including memories of Paul Ehrlich by Waldeyer.
  - Letter concerning special issue of the journal, "Die Farbenpost", 1954 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Letter concerning photo album given to Marianne Lander, 1954 February 26 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Heyman, G., Remarks on the presentation of the Paul Ehrlich and Ludwig Darmstaedter prizes to Professor Kauffman in the Paulskirche, 1964 March 14 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence dealing with Paul Ehrlich bank notes, 1988 October-May (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Schwerin from Bayerischer Rundfunk regarding a commemoration in Das Musikjournal Almanach, 1990 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies of Ehrlich correspondence with the Swedish Academy of Sciences, 1994 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Paul Ehrlich and William Bulloch correspondence, undated (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Letters containing titles of Japanese biography of Paul Ehrlich from Professor Dr. R. Shiga of Tokyo, undated (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Zwei handschriftliche schrieben von Professor Julius Morgenroth to Paul Ehrlich, [Two handwritten letters written by Professor Julius Morgenroth to Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Speeches, and Lectures
  Labels are handwritten by Paul Ehrlich
  - Letters to and from Paul Ehrlich (B-F) (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Letters to and from Paul Ehrlich (G-O) (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Letters to and from Paul Ehrlich (O-W) (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Transcriptions of letters to and from Paul Ehrlich, vol. [Sammlung Darmstaedter - Estate of Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Transcriptions of letters to and from Paul Ehrlich, vol. 2 [Sammlung Darmstaedter - Estate of Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Ehrlich's Report about the Institute for Serumforschung and Prüfung in Berlin-Steglitz, 1896-1899, and the Institute Experimentelle Therapie in Frankfurt, 1899-1900, 1896-1900 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Speakers at Paul Ehrlich's Wake (A list and excerpts from speeches), 1915 August 23 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Loewi, Dr. Otto, Research Professor of Pharmacology at the New York University School of Medicine, "Reflections on the Study of Medicine", an address given at the Richmond Area Visiting Center during a visit from May 10-28, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences "Paul Ehrlich Centennial", Vol. 59, Art. 2, pp. 141-276, 1954 September 23; 2 copies (Box 62, Folder 6)